Blanca MANCILLA

4265, rue Jean-Brillant Montréal (Québec) H3T 1P2, Canada +1.514.591.2007

Email: blancalmancilla@gmail.com

Blog: superspreadsheet.wordpress.com

github: github.com/bluciam

Academic Web: mancilla.web.cse.unsw.edu.au

Written, spoken: English, French, Spanish.

Other: German, B1 level currently in Goethe Institut.



LinkedIn

Professional Profile

I have +10 years of experience in Computer Science research and teaching, and over a year in Web development. I want to capitalize my skills and knowledge in working in a team to create unique products to shape the future, disseminate knowledge to empower capable minorities, to work in core problems. I am always learning and experimenting with current technologies, attending MeetUps, reading and writing technical blogs, or on Twitter.

Positions

2012–now Consultant, Montreal, Canada (Web developer and Technical Writer)

- · Backend developer: Test-driven development in Rails in a team of three (on going).
- · Web developer: From conception to Heroku deployment as sole developer in Ruby on Rails for a Montreal startup (testing stage).

https://evening-harbor-6988.herokuapp.com

· Design and front-end development using CSS and HTML of a static site.

http://vinka-creations.bitballoon.com

· Technical Writer: Rewrite developers' interviews as tax rebate claims and reports.

2004–2015 Faculty Member (in Computer Science), UNSW Australia, Sydney

- · Lecturer; theses supervisor, assessor and advisor.
- · Researcher, team member, documentation writer, software evaluator.
- · Assignment conception, specification, deployment and marking.
- · Course administrator, curriculum advisor and assessor.

2009–2012 Faculty Member, University of Technology, Sydney (UTS), Australia

- · Lecturer; curriculum redesigner; specification writer.
- 1993–1995 **Student Assistant** (Remote Sensing), Laval University, Québec, Canada
- 1991–1992 **System administrator**, IBM AS/400, Electro-Alloys, NY, USA

Computer skills snapshot

• **Web programming** in Ruby on Rails, testing, CSS and Bootstrap, HTML, hook up to third party services, (S3 Amazon Web Services, MailChimp, databases).

- · **Intermediate** in Python
- · **Beginner** in JavaScript, JQuery, Django.
- · Open source development tools, Linux, shell scripting, CLI, git, LTEX.
- **Teaching knowledge** in programming languages (C, Java, Haskell), geographical information systems applied to Civil Engineering, ArcGIS, human computer interaction, information systems, computer graphics.

Research Software

SuperSpreadSheet (S³), https://github.com/bluciam/superspreadsheet

The purpose of this project was to demonstrate the use of contextual electronic documents: case study, the multi-spreadsheet. It covered conception, research, design and implementation.

Anita Conti Mapping Server, https://github.com/bluciam/anita-jsp-2005

The ACMS project was developed as a proof of concept. Development iterations had to accommodate the constant change of requirements, tools and research discoveries. This prototype was developed for my PhD.

TransLucid Project, http://sourceforge.net/projects/translucid

As a team member, I was part of the design and planning stages of creating the TransLucid language. I devised the documentation structure and tailored it to different audiences. As the first user, I was the main interactive tester of the system.

Education

1999-2004	PhD, Computer Science, UNSW Australia, Sydney
1993-1995	MSc, Geomatic Sciences, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1992-1993	French as a second language, Laval University, Québec, Canada
1990	Seminar on Research, Summer Program, SUNY at Stony Brook, USA
1989-1991	BSc, Computer Electronic Science, Iona College, NY, USA
1984-1988	BEng, Computer Systems Engineering (four of five years), Industrial University of Santander (UIS), Colombia

Conference and Workshops Organization

2001-2002	<i>International Conference on Distributed Communities on the Web</i> , DCW 2002 Local Arrangements Chair: Webmaster; budget and conference manager.
2000 2002	
2000-2002	Women in Computing, UNSW, Director and founder:
	Liaison between community stakeholders; conception of events.
2000-2003	Girls in Science and Technology Workshops (an Anita Borg initiative),
	Founder, organizer, host: HTML, lego mindstorms and iMovie workshops.

Publications, http://plaice.web.cse.unsw.edu.au/archive/BLM

Total	28	Books	1	Book Chapters	1
		Journal Articles	5	Theses	2
		Conference Articles	17	Compilations	2